OLJA PRIYAKOVICH

COFFEE CONNOISSEUR • GLOBAL OPERATIONS & PRODUCTION MANAGER • CORPORATE COFFEE LEADER

GRAND RAPIDS, MICHIGAN • 1.415.254.0291 • LINKEDIN.COM/IN/OLJAPRIYAKOVICH • OLJAGOOLSBY@ME.COM

SUMMARY

Driven former coffee business owner with a passion for everything coffee. Experienced over 10 years as a coffee artist, leading teams, and developing businesses from farm to cup. Possesses a drive to excel in any given task, successful management skills, and deeply devoted to the company's mission. Demonstrated ability to maintain balance in agile work environments. Multilingual and willing to learn additional languages.

KEY PROFICIENCIES AND SKILLS

DATA-DRIVEN STRATEGY | BRANDING | STAKEHOLDER EXPERIENCE | MS OFFICE | PERFORMANCE-DRIVEN | BUSINESS GROWTH | TALENT ACQUISITION | B2B

EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF COFFEE | DROPBOX I SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA

2014-2021

Head of Coffee and managed successful global coffee operations in Manhattan, NY, Austin, TX, Seattle, WA, and Dublin, Ireland.

- Accountable for fully operational coffee program development, including managing unlimited budget for machine buying operations and successfully trained a staff of 25 across 6 locations globally for optimal coffee operations.
- Anticipated and managed wholesale operations, utilizing skilled negotiation skills as head green coffee buyer on a weekly basis, developed strategic business relationships with stakeholders; reduced company's wholesale budget by 10%.
- Sourced, hired, and trained 2 skilled baristas in each coffee location, trained in-depth with espresso machines, roast blends, inventory, and the entire process of coffee for optimal Q/A.
- Presenter and speaker in-class presentations for over 6 years, experienced answering questions, and communicating full scope of the coffee process for employees within various departments.

OWNER | 2GIRLROASTER | SAUSALITO, CALIFORNIA

2011-2014

- Led and managed a fully functional coffee roasting-only operation in a versatile role; responsible for all operations from farm to cup in a dynamic and collaborative business partnership.
- Innovated and implemented client-focused branding strategies, successfully developed the company's vision and implementation with collaboration from skilled graphic designers and marketing strategists.
- Led the entire production of coffee process, negotiated best prices for wholesale international coffee; increased profit margins and strategies each succeeding year.

MANAGER OF RESTAURANT I CIBO | SAUSALITO, CALIFORNIA

2009-2013

Head barista made accountable for managing and leading a team, included training 4-5 staff successfully in all coffee operations and procedures.

EDUCATION

Cornerstone University | Bachelor of Business Management Personal Interests: Enjoys running, skiing, boating, and traveling.

2007